Speaker 1: Now, you may think that I'm raising this document before you, this plan for how to kill healthcare, and that maybe it doesn't have any bearance on the real debate here, but it absolutely does. These talking points are being echoed in this very chamber. In this very chamber, in order to kill healthcare. Let's see. Well, here
we go. Frank
Speaker 1: Lunt's memo, that's his
Speaker 2: memo.
Speaker 2: on
Speaker 1: how to kill health
Speaker 2: care came out in April.
It says
Speaker 2: talking point number five, health care denial horror stories from Canada and other countries do resonate, but you have to humanize them. You'll notice we recommend the phrase "government takeover" rather than "government run" or "government controlled." Why? Because "government takeover" sounds even scarier.
So what
Speaker 2: did we hear on the floor of this chamber from our minority leader
Speaker 3: just recently? I quote:
Speaker 3: Americans are concerned
Speaker 2: about a government takeover of healthcare, and for good reason. And it goes on. So recognize that that is a point that's coming from a document about how to kill healthcare, not a responsible debate about the plan we have
in front of
Speaker 2: us. Well, let's take a look at another example: Franklin's memo. His memo, talking points three
and four,
Time is a
Speaker 2: government healthcare killer. Nothing else
Speaker 3: turns people against government takeover of healthcare than the expectation that this plan will result in delayed and
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): denied treatment. The arguments against the plan—now note that this is about a plan that wasn't
Speaker 2: written. It's about any plan put forward. The arguments against this plan, but it's also centered around politicians, bureaucrats in Washington. Note the emphasis on saying that the plan will result in delays and denied treatment.
And what
Speaker 2: have we heard on the floor of this chamber from the minority leader?
We have
Speaker 2: heard, just recently, and I quote, "Americans don't want to be forced by bureaucrats,"
Speaker 3: that comes right out of those talking points, "to give up their private health care plan, to be pushed into a Washington-run government plan," right out of those talking points. They don't want to wait two years for surgery.
And they
Speaker 2: don't want to be told they're too old for surgery.
All
Speaker 2: of this, straight out of
this roadmap, my
Speaker 2: friends, it is irresponsible, in the face of 50 million Americans without health care, with working Americans in every one of our states going bankrupt as they struggle with health care expenses, it's irresponsible to utilize a
roadmap
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): of rhetoric that comes
from polling
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): about how to scare people. That's irresponsible.
Speaker 5: What we need to do today is lay out a plan on how we can create affordable, accessible health care for every single American.